It was precisely this political and social suppression, coupled with decades of colonialism and miseducation that slowly eroded the significance of the Arabic script in the region. All of these countries once used Arabic. Now it's just the green and the blue. To put it simply, the Arabic script is dying. In postcolonial Arab countries functioning in an increasingly globalized world, it is a growing alarm that less and less people are using the Arabic script to communicate. As I was studying my master's in Italy, I noticed myself missing Arabic. I missed looking at the letters, digesting their meaning. So one day, I walked into one of the biggest libraries in Italy in search of an Arabic book. I was surprised to find that this is what they had under the category of "Arabic/Middle Eastern books." (Laughter) Fear, terrorism and destruction. One word: ISIS. My heart ached that this is how we are portrayed to the world, even from a literary perspective. I asked myself: Whatever happened to the world-renowned writers like Naguib Mahfouz, Khalil Gibran, iconic poets like Mutanabbi, Nizar Qabbani? Think about this. The cultural products of an entire region of the world, as rich, as diverse, have been deemed redundant, if not ignored altogether. The cultural products of an entire region of the world have been barred from imparting any kind of real impact on global media productions and contemporary social discourse. And then I reminded myself of my number one belief: design can change the world. All you need is for someone to catch a glimpse of your work, feel, connect. And so I started. I thought about how can I stop the world from seeing us as evil, as terrorists of this planet, and start perceiving us as equals, fellow humans? How can I save and honor the Arabic script and share it with other people, other cultures? And then it hit me: What if I combined the two most significant symbols
Fue precisamente esta represión política y social, sumada a décadas de colonialismo y mala educación lo que erosionó lentamente el significado de la escritura árabe en la región. Todos estos países solían usar el árabe. Ahora son solo los verdes y los azules. En términos simples, la escritura árabe está muriendo. En los países árabes postcoloniales que funcionan en un mundo cada vez más globalizado es una creciente preocupación que cada vez menos gente se comunica con escritura árabe. Mientras hacía mi maestría en Italia, me di cuenta de que extrañaba el árabe. Extrañaba ver las letras, digerir su significado. Un día entré a una de las bibliotecas más grandes de Italia buscando un libro en árabe. Me sorprendió que tuvieran esto en la categoría de "Libros árabes y de Medio Oriente". (Risas) Miedo, terrorismo y destrucción. Ona palabra: ISIS. Me dolió en el alma que en el mundo nos vieran así, aun desde un punto de vista literario. Me pregunté: ¿qué pasó con los escritores de fama mundial como Naguib Mahfuz, Khalil Gibran? ¿O los poetas icónicos como Mutanabbi, Nizar Qabbani? Piensen en esto. El producto cultural de toda una región tan rica y tan diversa como esta se ha dejado de lado, o incluso ignorado por completo. El producto cultural de toda una región no tiene la posibilidad de marcar un impacto importante en los medios a nivel mundial y en el discurso social de actualidad. Y después me acordé de mi creencia número uno: el diseño puede cambiar el mundo. Solo hace falta que alguien le dé una ojeada a tu trabajo, sienta algo, conecte. Entonces empecé. Pensé, ¿cómo puedo hacer que el mundo deje de vernos como el mal, como los terroristas del planeta, y empiece a vernos como iguales, como humanos? ¿Cómo puedo salvar y honrar la escritura árabe y compartirla con otras personas, con otras culturas? Y ahí se me ocurrió: ¿Por qué no combinar los dos símbolos más significativos
of innocence and Arab identity? Maybe then people could resonate. What's more pure, innocent and fun as LEGO? It's a universal child's toy. You play with them, you build with them, and with them, you imagine endless possibilities. My eureka moment was to find a bilingual solution for Arabic education, because effective communication and education is the road to more tolerant communities. However, the Arabic and Latin scripts do not only represent different worlds but also create technical difficulties for both Eastern and Western communities on a daily basis. There are so many reasons why Arabic and Latin are different, but here are some of the main ones. Yes, both use upward and downward strokes, but have completely different baselines. Arabic tends to be more calligraphic and connectivity is important to the Arabic language, whose letters have to be mostly joined in order to articulate a given word. It also uses an entirely different system of punctuation and diacritics. But most importantly, Arabic has no capital letters. Instead it has four different letter forms: initial, medial, isolated and final. I want to introduce the Arabic language to young learners, foreign speakers, but most importantly help refugees integrate to their host societies through creating a bilingual learning system, a two-way flow of communication. And I called it "Let's Play." The idea is to simply create a fun and engaging way of learning Modern Standard Arabic through LEGO. These are the two words. "Let's Play." Every colored bar marks an Arabic letter. As you can see, the letter is explained in form, sound and examples of words in function, in addition to the equivalent in Latin. Together, they form a fun pocket book with the 29 Arabic letters and the four different forms, plus a 400-word dictionary. So this is how the page looks like. You have the letter, the transliteration in Latin and the description underneath. I'll take you through the process. So first in my tiny studio in Florence, I built the letters. I photographed each letter separately,
de la inocencia y la identidad árabe? Tal vez así la gente podría notarlo. ¿Qué puede ser más puro, inocente y divertido que los LEGO? Es un juguete universal. Juegas con ellos, construyes con ellos, y con ellos te imaginas infinitas posibilidades. Mi momento de inspiración llegó en forma de solución bilingüe para enseñar árabe, porque la comunicación efectiva y la educación hacen posible una mayor tolerancia en las comunidades. Sin embargo, la escritura árabe y latina no solo representan mundos diferentes sino que crean dificultades técnicas para las comunidades orientales y occidentales todos los días. El alfabeto árabe y el latino difieren por muchas razones; aquí hay algunas de las principales. Sí, los dos tienen trazos ascendentes y descendentes, pero tienen líneas de base completamente diferentes. El árabe tiende a ser más caligráfico y la conectividad es importante porque las letras deben estar mayormente unidas para poder articular una palabra. También usa un sistema de puntuación y diacríticos totalmente distintos. Pero, más importante aún, el árabe no tiene mayúsculas. En cambio, las letras tienen cuatro formas distintas: inicial, media, aislada y final. Quiero presentar el idioma árabe a los jóvenes, a los extranjeros, pero sobre todo quiero ayudar a los refugiados a integrarse en las sociedades que los reciben, a través de un sistema de aprendizaje bilingüe, un flujo de comunicación bidireccional. Lo llamé "Let's play". La idea es simplemente crear una manera divertida y atractiva de aprender árabe estándar moderno usando LEGO. Estas son las dos palabras: "Let's Play". Cada barra de color marca una letra árabe. Como ven, para cada letra se explica la forma, el sonido y ejemplos de uso de la palabra, además del equivalente en alfabeto latino. El set completo forma un entretenido libro de bolsillo con las 29 letras árabes en las cuatro formas diferentes, más un diccionario de 400 palabras. La página se ve así. Tiene la letra, la transliteración en escritura latina, y una descripción debajo. Les explico el proceso. Primero armé las letras en mi diminuto estudio, en Florencia. Fotografié cada letra por separado,
and then I retouched every letter and chose the correct color background and typefaces to use. Ultimately, I created the full letter set, which is 29 letters times four different forms. That's 116 letters build just in one week.
y luego retoqué cada una y elegí el color de fondo y los tipos de letra. Y así terminé el set de letras completo. que son 29 letras por cuatro formas diferentes. O sea, 116 letras en solo una semana.
I believe that information should and can be fun, portable. This book is the final product, which I would eventually like to publish
Creo que la información debería y puede ser divertida y portátil. Este libro es el producto terminado, que algún día voy a publicar
and translate into as many languages in the world, so that Arabic teaching and learning becomes fun, easy and accessible globally. With this book, I hope to save my nation's beautiful script. (Applause) Thank you. Working on this project was a form of visual meditation, like a Sufi dance, a prayer to a better planet. One set of building blocks made two languages. LEGO is just a metaphor. It's because we are all made of the same building unit, is that I can see a future where the barriers between people all come tumbling down. So no matter how ugly the world around us gets, or how many discouraging books on ISIS, the terrorist group, and not Isis, the ancient Egyptian goddess, continue to be published, I will keep building one colorful world. Shukran, which means "thank you." (Applause) Thank you. Thank you so much. Thank you.
y traducir a la mayor cantidad de idiomas posibles para que enseñar y aprender árabe sea divertido, fácil y accesible en todo el mundo. Con este libro, espero salvar el futuro de la hermosa escritura de mi país. (Aplausos) Gracias. Trabajar en este proyecto fue como una forma de meditación visual, como una danza sufí, una plegaria para un planeta mejor. Un solo set de bloques dio a luz a dos idiomas. LEGO es solo una metáfora. Y dado que todos estamos hechos de los mismos bloques, me imagino un futuro donde se desmoronan las barreras entre las personas. Entonces, no importa cuán feo sea el mundo que nos rodea, o cuántos libros desalentadores sobre ISIS, el grupo terrorista, no Isis, la antigua diosa egipcia, sigan publicándose, yo voy a seguir construyendo un mundo de colores. Shukran, que quiere decir "gracias". (Aplausos) Gracias. Muchas gracias. Gracias.